<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[ChristopherTong]]></title>
  <link href="http://christophertong.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://christophertong.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-22T20:37:56+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://christophertong.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keep the Socks Dry - Part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://christophertong.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/keep-dry-socks-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T06:44:11+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://christophertong.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/keep-dry-socks-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Travel experiences</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keep the Socks Dry - What I Learned While Traveling]]></title>
    <link href="http://christophertong.github.io/blog/2014/03/29/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-29T11:55:48+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://christophertong.github.io/blog/2014/03/29/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since graduating in May of last year, I have been lucky enough to spend time in 20 cities, 11 countries, in 3 continents. Some nights I staked out in swanky company hotel rooms. Others were far more humble &ndash; freezing on a stranger&rsquo;s couch, hoping that the person who used the sheets before me kept good hygiene. During my travels I made some very poor decisions which I have aggregated here so that you and I will not make the same mistakes again. Here are the top few things that I wish I knew last May<!--more-->:</p>

<h2>Nothing will ever go as planned</h2>

<p>Plans are important. I am a big fan of reading ahead, writing an itinerary, finding lodging etc.. With that said, plans never work out! It is my belief that for the most part, we as human beings are very at guaging time. This holds especially true for newbie travellers. There is so much that an inexperienced traveller like myself (and perhaps you) do not take into account. Certain places may take longer to get to than expected, taking more time at sights is a common occurance, and a rainstorm can ruin any well planned day. If you are a compulsive planner like me, try to embrace the uncertainty. Plans are good guidelines but in trying to make every single sight on the to do list, you will miss out on many experiences. The awesome graffiti on the wall or the pigeons in the town square, these small things are what will make you smile looking back at your trip.</p>

<h2>Don&rsquo;t be greedy</h2>

<p>In Paris, my friend and I bought the 2 day museum pass- worst decision ever. We saw attractions in that two day span. But in our attempt to &ldquo;break even&rdquo; we left no time for reflection and to take it all in (my fault). Running around Paris from one sight to another, looking to pack the closing times in the perfect order to see as many museums and monuments as possible. The two days were dead tiring and we found ourselves at the edge of our nerves.</p>

<p>In another instance, another friend and I found ourselves sludging through the October rain in Kyoto. We arrived from Osaka at 11am and were to return that same night. There is so much to do in Kyoto and we wanted to both see the sights and at the same time take in the local culture by walking through the city streets. When you add in the unceasing, miserable drizzle that seemed to permulate every nook in your clothing, there is simply not enough time to do it all. By around sunset, we could that we could not make the closing time for the place that my friend wanted to go to the most- the Golden Pavilion. To be so close but not able to see it was a bummer we didn&rsquo;t know when our next opportunity would be to return to Kyoto. Looking back, we had some amazing experiences that day. A few months removed from the trip, my fondest memory was in fact the beauty of the city drenched in rain. As a side note, I am planning to go back to Kyoto this June.</p>

<h2>Be considerate of your travel buddy</h2>

<p>Its not just about you! Do not take your travel companion for granted. Long trips are not always rosy and have their rocky moments. Companions are a great source of emotional support. The shared experience can create a lasting bond and turn an acquaintance into a life long friend. Sooo, realize their decision to travel with you is a choice and a sacrifice. Your companion have things he or she wants to do, but they decided to spend time with you instead. Make the conscious decision to do the same. Even if you didn’t &ldquo;accomplish&rdquo; everything that you wanted to do on your trip, you will look back and cherish the memories made with the friend.</p>

<h2>Beautiful things are beautiful, Ugly things are beautiful too</h2>

<p>The Eiffel tower was stunning. But one of the most memorable moments for me was a walk through a dilapidated neighborhood in my Dad&rsquo;s hometown in China. Storefronts vacated and building bricks lay scattered in the middle of the street. There were no tourists and it was hard to imagine that less than 15 years ago, the area was the most crowded in the city. There are many areas- even in Paris, that will not make the postcard. These are the everyday parts of the city and for me they are some of the most interesting places to visit. If you have the time, try to get off the beaten path. Go on an aimless run and try to get lost. It can make you appreciate that city as well as your home so much more.</p>

<h2>Keep in mind the kindness of others</h2>

<p>I was very lucky to have had friends (and even strangers) show me around many of the places I visightd. Some of these people I was not particularly close with, others I have not talked to in years. Keep in mind that I did not travel exclusively on weekends, they all had their own life. My college friends had papers due and finals to study for. My older friends had work. You will be surprised at how willing people are to show you around if you simply reach out. Most people take pride in their town and the best tour guides are always locals.</p>

<p>In England, I tried Couchsurfing as a form of lodging and luckily a few people agreed to take me in. The nights sleeping in a stranger&rsquo;s apartment were some of the most meaningful of my travels. One night I stayed at a struggling students place, the next at an IBankers apartment off Baker Street. Couchsurfing allows the surfer to see the city without the rose tinted glasses. Of course remain vigilant and act with common sense. But also keep an open mind and be respectful of others.</p>

<h2>Find time to travel alone</h2>

<p>Traveling alone can be daunting, especially when travelling outside the city or in a country where you do not speak the language. But there are a few reasons to at least try it once. First, it is easier to meet people when you are alone. Go to a hostel and start talking to people. Some people you may have a great conversation with over dinner and never see again, another may be your next travel companion, that uncertainty can be thrilling. A fellow resident that stayed in my hostel in Amsterdam offered to show me around Zurich a few weeks later. Second, travelling alone allows the most time for self reflection. You don&rsquo;t have to worry about others, about the trip</p>

<h2>Keep a journal</h2>

<p>During your travels, you are bound to come up with a golden epiphany to the secret of life. Do not expect to remember said epiphany after downing a few drinks at the local pub- for me that would be approximately two drinks. Keep a journal, write about your day or jot down a few thoughts during the down times. Thirty years from now, you can read the entries and look back at what a life changing experience this trip was and also what naive thoughts you had at the time.</p>

<h2>Shut up and listen</h2>

<p> Travelling is as much about meeting people as it is about seeing the sights. That means meeting like minded travellers, locals, and also people that come from different backgrounds with different points of view. Try to see the world from their point of view. Also, listen to the goings on the street. People&rsquo;s daily interactions at the park or at the coffee shops, it can tell you much about the way you are living your life. Lastly, listen to yourself. Sometimes what you have to tell yourself might not be flattering, but listen closely and you may learn some true things about yourself. Travelling allows you to see the true nature of others.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
