<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[ChristopherTong]]></title>
  <link href="http://christophertong.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://christophertong.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-13T22:38:55+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://christophertong.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Data Blurs]]></title>
    <link href="http://christophertong.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/when-data-blurs/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T06:44:11+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://christophertong.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/when-data-blurs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I have the chance, I go to the company library to read. On this particular afternoon I picked up MIT Sloan Management Review&rsquo;s issue dedicated to data analytics. Conceding to the fact that I can never escape from work, I sat down and flipped through an editorial to this statement: as we live in an age of data abundance, upper management in all industries are hurriedly attempting to use new forms of data to make business decisions. To me, the &ldquo;hurried&rdquo; mentality described by the editor is a primary reason why many companies still have not succeed in smartly utilizing their data. I spend an absurd amount of my waking hours making sense of numbers and can comfortably claim that sometimes numbers just do not have much to say- at least not on things that a manager may know how to act on. <!--more-->Too many traditional business minds see this new trend of information abundance as a crystal ball where plaguing questions originating from the dawn of the industry will automatically be answered. Or worse yet, they see it as a mathematical proof that long held theories are fundamentally sound. Managers that feel a great urgency to gain insight from this crystal ball are doomed to the realization that the answers they provide may be more murky than expected.</p>

<h3>Information gathering through Surveys</h3>

<p>One of the root causes for the current infatuation with big data is the variety of sources that can be analyzed. Sales and shipments use to be the extent of information that an advanced intelligence team had to analyze their core business. Text, geospatial and clicktimes are fast becoming common commodities. But in many instances, companies not named Linkedin, Facebook or Google do not have the resources necessary for advanced research. Companies want insight on how consumers interact with their product. Enter the survey. On a scale of 1-10, how satisfied were you of this experience? How likely are you to recommend this product to your friends? With surveys, companies can analyze responses by region, age group and social economic status. Overall this source of information gathering is a crude way to quantify a previously unquantifiable attribute. Now with technology, qualitative analysis has suddenly become quantifiable and as such there is no actually determent to using surveys as an inadequate placeholder.</p>

<p>There are inherent problems with using survey and reviews as a measurement of how a consumer truly feel about a product or company. Online popup surveys like those offered by SurveyMonkey give prizes on completion that will bias the selection of respondents. In addition, taking online reviews on face value is a very dangerous proposition. To paraphrase Steve Jobs, people don&rsquo;t know what they want and studies have shown that new reviewers on online retail or movie review sites are affected by previous reviews. (This may actually be a clever way for companies to influence consumer behavior but I digress.) Imagine a company moving into new product categories or implementing widespread strategies drawn from the conclusions of survey based studies &ndash; it is more common than you think.</p>

<h3>Knowing what to measure, Knowing it is measurable</h3>

<p>A recent Atlantic article detailed the methods researchers in Ohio State University used to find out &ldquo;how many times men think about sex in a day&rdquo;. The method is called experience sampling. Subjects download an app with buttons amount which are labelled food, sex and others. They are then asked to click one of the buttons each time they have the thought. Aside from how these techniques can greatly influence the outcome of the study, my main takeaway from this article is the difficultly in defining what is being measured. Since thoughts have no unit of measurement, what exactly constitutes as a &ldquo;thought&rdquo;? In marketing teams, impressions are measureable and so are clicktimes, but in actuality is what the company wants to know answerable using these measurements? Sometimes no and sometimes maybe, but almost never an absolute yes.</p>

<h3>Ethnography as a Supplement</h3>

<p>With these newfound abilities to quantify everything about a user, old fashioned targeted user ethnographic research is often left at the wayside. Ethnography studies the qualitative rather than the quantitative aspects of a subject. Instead of looking at the aggregate, the ethnographic style of research will dive deeply into the lives of a relatively small number of people- focusing on their environment and social networks. By understanding the individual personally the researchers hopes to garner insight on the group he belongs to collectively.</p>

<p>Design firms such as IDEO typically conduct this type of research, but ethnography is not commonly practiced in the business realm. Corporate researchers obsessed with benchmarking and impressions often forget that at the end of the day, what the user notices most and what keeps them using the product is function. Managers might contend that design is for Apple. The reality, as Nest, Tesla and Square (a b2b company) have shown, it is exactly the industries that have yet to be disrupted that need to start focusing more on products and less on sales, supply chains and price points.</p>

<h3>Sharing data</h3>

<p>In the current frenzy to collect and analyze as much data as possible, what is often left from the fold is that much of the data might not be useful for the company but potentially can be very useful for a partner. Facebook, Linkedin and Twitter (amount many others in the tech industry) have all made their information available to the public through the use of platforms. Companies in the more traditional hardware business can learn from this type of information sharing and may even find business opportunities in this endeavor. At the end of the day, the more knowledgeable your partners are the better business is for you.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>We are currently still in the infancy of the information age for most industries. This has left business executives anxious to show their analysis capabilities. Like stockpiling weapons, companies greedily hoard information in hopes of one-upping the competition. Meta reporting &ndash; or reports about reports is a common theme in corporate. These behaviors essentially miss the point. Just because you can does not mean you should. More data does not mean more analysis, it means smarter analysis. Sometimes that may even mean not being swayed by the analysis. With everything quantifiable, it is now more important than ever to focus on the qualitative aspects of the your product, the quantitative aspects can serve as the guide. Without direction, it is easy to be lost in this ocean of information.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple Things I Learned While Traveling]]></title>
    <link href="http://christophertong.github.io/blog/2014/03/29/simple-things-i-learned/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-29T11:55:48+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://christophertong.github.io/blog/2014/03/29/simple-things-i-learned</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since graduating in May of last year, I have been lucky enough to spend time in 20 cities, 11 countries, in 3 continents. Some nights I staked out in swanky company hotel rooms. Others were far more humble &ndash; freezing on a stranger&rsquo;s couch, hoping that the person who used the sheets before me kept good hygiene. During my travels I made some very poor decisions which I have aggregated here so that you and I will not make the same mistakes again. Here are the top few things that I wish I knew last May<!--more-->:</p>

<h2>Nothing will ever go as planned</h2>

<p>Plans are important. I am a big fan of reading ahead, writing an itinerary, finding lodging etc.. With that said, plans never work out! It is my belief that for the most part, we as human beings are very at guaging time. This holds especially true for newbie travellers. There is so much that an inexperienced traveller like myself (and perhaps you) do not take into account. Certain places may take longer to get to than expected, taking more time at sights is a common occurance, and a rainstorm can ruin any well planned day. If you are a compulsive planner like me, try to embrace the uncertainty. Plans are good guidelines but in trying to make every single sight on the to do list, you will miss out on many experiences. The awesome graffiti on the wall or the pigeons in the town square, these small things are what will make you smile looking back at your trip.</p>

<h2>Don&rsquo;t be greedy</h2>

<p>In Paris, my friend and I bought the 2 day museum pass- worst decision ever. We saw attractions in that two day span. But in our attempt to &ldquo;break even&rdquo; we left no time for reflection and to take it all in (my fault). Running around Paris from one sight to another, looking to pack the closing times in the perfect order to see as many museums and monuments as possible. The two days were dead tiring and we found ourselves at the edge of our nerves.</p>

<p>In another instance, another friend and I found ourselves sludging through the October rain in Kyoto. We arrived from Osaka at 11am and were to return that same night. There is so much to do in Kyoto and we wanted to both see the sights and at the same time take in the local culture by walking through the city streets. When you add in the unceasing, miserable drizzle that seemed to permulate every nook in your clothing, there is simply not enough time to do it all. By around sunset, we could that we could not make the closing time for the place that my friend wanted to go to the most- the Golden Pavilion. To be so close but not able to see it was a bummer we didn&rsquo;t know when our next opportunity would be to return to Kyoto. Looking back, we had some amazing experiences that day. A few months removed from the trip, my fondest memory was in fact the beauty of the city drenched in rain. As a side note, I am planning to go back to Kyoto this June.</p>

<h2>Be considerate of your travel buddy</h2>

<p>Its not just about you! Do not take your travel companion for granted. Long trips are not always rosy and have their rocky moments. Companions are a great source of emotional support. The shared experience can create a lasting bond and turn an acquaintance into a life long friend. Sooo, realize their decision to travel with you is a choice and a sacrifice. Your companion have things he or she wants to do, but they decided to spend time with you instead. Make the conscious decision to do the same. Even if you didn’t &ldquo;accomplish&rdquo; everything that you wanted to do on your trip, you will look back and cherish the memories made with the friend.</p>

<h2>Beautiful things are beautiful, Ugly things are beautiful too</h2>

<p>The Eiffel tower was stunning. But one of the most memorable moments for me was a walk through a dilapidated neighborhood in my Dad&rsquo;s hometown in China. Storefronts vacated and building bricks lay scattered in the middle of the street. There were no tourists and it was hard to imagine that less than 15 years ago, the area was the most crowded in the city. There are many areas- even in Paris, that will not make the postcard. These are the everyday parts of the city and for me they are some of the most interesting places to visit. If you have the time, try to get off the beaten path. Go on an aimless run and try to get lost. It can make you appreciate that city as well as your home so much more.</p>

<h2>Keep in mind the kindness of others</h2>

<p>I was very lucky to have had friends (and even strangers) show me around many of the places I visightd. Some of these people I was not particularly close with, others I have not talked to in years. Keep in mind that I did not travel exclusively on weekends, they all had their own life. My college friends had papers due and finals to study for. My older friends had work. You will be surprised at how willing people are to show you around if you simply reach out. Most people take pride in their town and the best tour guides are always locals.</p>

<p>In England, I tried Couchsurfing as a form of lodging and luckily a few people agreed to take me in. The nights sleeping in a stranger&rsquo;s apartment were some of the most meaningful of my travels. One night I stayed at a struggling students place, the next at an IBankers apartment off Baker Street. Couchsurfing allows the surfer to see the city without the rose tinted glasses. Of course remain vigilant and act with common sense. But also keep an open mind and be respectful of others.</p>

<h2>Find time to travel alone</h2>

<p>Traveling alone can be daunting, especially when travelling outside the city or in a country where you do not speak the language. But there are a few reasons to at least try it once. First, it is easier to meet people when you are alone. Go to a hostel and start talking to people. Some people you may have a great conversation with over dinner and never see again, another may be your next travel companion, that uncertainty can be thrilling. A fellow resident that stayed in my hostel in Amsterdam offered to show me around Zurich a few weeks later. Second, travelling alone allows the most time for self reflection. You don&rsquo;t have to worry about others, about the trip</p>

<h2>Keep a journal</h2>

<p>During your travels, you are bound to come up with a golden epiphany to the secret of life. Do not expect to remember said epiphany after downing a few drinks at the local pub- for me that would be approximately two drinks. Keep a journal, write about your day or jot down a few thoughts during the down times. Thirty years from now, you can read the entries and look back at what a life changing experience this trip was and also what naive thoughts you had at the time.</p>

<h2>Shut up and listen</h2>

<p> Travelling is as much about meeting people as it is about seeing the sights. That means meeting like minded travellers, locals, and also people that come from different backgrounds with different points of view. Try to see the world from their point of view. Also, listen to the goings on the street. People&rsquo;s daily interactions at the park or at the coffee shops, it can tell you much about the way you are living your life. Lastly, listen to yourself. Sometimes what you have to tell yourself might not be flattering, but listen closely and you may learn some true things about yourself. Travelling allows you to see the true nature of others.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Displays and Cameras]]></title>
    <link href="http://christophertong.github.io/blog/2013/10/26/displays-cameras/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-26T07:03:28+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://christophertong.github.io/blog/2013/10/26/displays-cameras</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An article on the future relationship between displays and cameras. I begin by decomposing the function of the television and camera. The next sections argue that camera technology will enable users to have a more natural way for human to computer interaction. Likewise, the camera will act as a tool in human to human communication.<!--more--></p>

<h3>What are televisions?</h3>

<p>Watching TV is a collective experience done in a group setting as televisions allow multiple users to view the output of information from a single source.
The current market trends toward smaller screens for personal consumption by a single user. Smaller screens such as tablets offer more control over the immediate content that flows from the screen. Due to touch screen capability and a screen that is arm’s length away, the user can quickly interact with the content through games, web browsing, watching videos, reading or more commonly as a combination of the aforementioned.</p>

<p>Yet contrary to tablet screens, the single function of a television is for the user to only consume information. The size of screens keeps users at a distance, hindering content interaction. The traditional approach to interacting with content on the television has been through the use of the remote control. Remote controls are a very effective way of managing content in the past. It allowed users to adjust sound as well as sift through channels while providing a simple user interface via a system of real buttons. With practice, a viewer can navigate without taking the eyes off of the television. However television navigation strategies are no longer efficient in navigating the ever increasing content and entertainment options. Whereas media companies controlled the output of content in traditional television, current consumption trends toward users sifting through the vast amount of information on the web and dictating what they want to spend time consuming.</p>

<p>The benefit televisions have over tablets is the social atmosphere that televisions provide in the space of the real world. Many people can participate in watching television at the same time. Users can share in the joy of a spectacular goal or discuss plots after watching a movie together. When the television is activated in the background, all users in the general vicinity are funneled the same information. It is not uncommon for televisions to be on in the background during meal times. The television allows individuals to focus on select aspects of information being displayed and dictates talking points of conversation with other individuals while still keeping unobtrusive to the general environment. For example, when the news is in the background, a user might discuss news stories with those around him. Tablets allow users to interact with others outside of their general vicinity. Televisions on the other hand are optimized for group settings with interactions occurring in the real world.</p>

<h3>What is a Camera?</h3>

<p>As the old saying goes “A picture is worth a thousand words.” Along with the keyboard, the camera is an input device that captures pictures and other media output we as users consume.  In many instances, humans are much more efficient when analyzing pictures than when analyzing words. In the case of Da Vinci’s Mona Lisa, the viewer can process the subtle colors of the trees and hills in the background, the flow of Mona Lisa’s dress, even the subtle smile on the subject, with a simple glance much more efficiently than in the form of a descriptive article.</p>

<p>Words on the other hand prove superior in its relative preciseness compared to visuals. Words allow us to convey our thoughts and emotions as directly as possible. This is the reason why our interaction with computers is done through words. While it is difficult enough for humans to interpret the true emotions that Mono Lisa is trying to display, it is near impossible for a computer to do so. With words, we are able to direct our commands to the computer with as little ambiguity as possible.</p>

<p>The camera’s most common function is still to enable social interaction between users that are not in the same geographical location. However, as the eye of the computer, camera’s will allow computers to soon have the ability to interpret motions, smiles, eye movement, sounds- all the social interactions that humans have been using to communicate for millennia. Cameras will become the most natural way of human to computer interaction.</p>

<h3>Controlling Televisions</h3>

<p>Most people hail the scene in “Minority Report” as the future of human computer interaction. The protagonist in the movie controls the computer by navigating through a 3d hologram with his hands. What many do not realize is that to stand in front of a screen with hands contorted is very tiring. The value of the traditional remote control is that by using tactile buttons, the user is able to completely focus on the television while parsing through channels. Remote control apps on the phone lack this tactile output and as a consequence users must draw their attention away from the television in order to navigate the remote. App remotes also disrupt the flow of second screen usage. Users simultaneously use their tablet or smartphone screen to access content while watching the television. By having the smartphone double as a remote control users would have to switch back and forth from the remote to access controls.</p>

<p>Recent startup company Tobii made it possible for users to instantaneously control Windows 8 with their eyes. The technology tracks eye movements and is precise to the pixel. However, how would the television realize when the user is viewing the movie and when he or she actually wants to bring up the television menu? This is a design problem for remote control apps. New app designs should allow users to dictate when they want to toggle from movie to menu. In this setup, the remote app will feature only one button- no more than two. One tap to toggle menu mode, a tap to select content after the eye focuses and a final tap to switch out.  To solve the problem of second screen disruption, developers can implement technologies similar to Smart Pause in Galaxy S4 phones. Cameras can enable the tablet to realize when the user’s attention is switched to the television screen and will switch seamlessly to the remote app.</p>

<h3>The Television as a Gateway to the Mind</h3>

<p> Eye tracking technologies such as Tobii combined with light field cameras like Lytro have the possibility to create an immersive viewing experience. Lytro cameras create pictures that can be refocused. It is easy to imagine the incredible visual experience of having eye tracking technologies as the input to control light field enabled pictures. A potentially greater use of eye tracking technologies is to allow for another form of human to human communication. Imagine placing a baby in front of a Tobii enabled screen. Parents and doctors can track what the infant is looking at and can in a sense see through the eyes of the infant. Other use cases include autism patients, language barrier situations, and perhaps even pet interaction.  Future research is needed on the feasibility of these scenarios.</p>

<p>Compared to smartphones and tablets, televisions have a much longer use life. Televisions are expensive and people do not switch televisions on each new iteration. Once purchased, televisions traditionally do not provide user information of marketable value for the manufacturer. However, second screen technologies now allow manufacturers to track what users browse while watching television. Assuming correlation between what users watch and what they browse on their smartphones or tablet, this allows marketers to have potentially valuable information about what content on televisions are effective- in a sense a second degree click through rate. There is no doubt that content when streamed to users’ living rooms or bars, have always allowed content interaction in ways that marketers may not have perceived. Marketers now have information on this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
